Maxwell Anderson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Maxwell Anderson Papers 1920-1989 (bulk 1920-1955)
MS009008
Anderson, Maxwell, 1888-1959
50 items
6 containers plus 1 oversize
3 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Playwright. Correspondence and scripts, including drafts and galleys deposited in the Library of Congress Copyright Office.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Anderson, Maxwell, 1888-1959--Correspondence.; Anderson, Maxwell, 1888-1959.; Monro, Harold, 1879-1932--Correspondence.
Subjects
Drama--Stories, plots, etc.; Motion picture plays, American.
Occupations
Dramatists.
Provenance
The papers of Maxwell Anderson, playwright, were given to the Library of Congress by Anderson in 1956. Some items were converted to gift in 1956, and a substantial addition was received by transfer from the Rare Book and Special Collections Division in 1964 and 1975 and from the Library of Congress Copyright Office in 1966. Further additions were received by purchase, 1961, and by gifts of Kenneth Anderson, 1943, and Alan H. Anderson and Mrs. Gertrude Anderson, 1989.
Access and Restrictions
Restrictions apply governing the use, photoduplication, or publication of items in this collection. Consult a reference librarian in the Manuscript Division concerning these restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Maxwell Anderson (1888-1959) span the years 1920-1989, with the bulk of the items concentrated in the period 1920-1955. The collection consists of letters to and from Harold Monro and copies of various plays and screenplays by Anderson, including scripts which he submitted for copyright to the Library of Congress Copyright Office. Among the drafts, corrected galleys, and annotated copies are scripts for “Anne of the Thousand Days,” “Joan of Lorraine,” “The Eve of St. Mark,” and “What Price Glory.”
Arrangement of the Papers
The copyright deposits are arranged chronologically. Other scripts are arranged alphabetically by title.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1920 (Box 1)
- Scripts (Box 1)
  - Copyright Deposits* (Box 1)
    - 1925, "Outside Looking In" (Box 1)
    - 1926, "Saturday's Children" (Box 1)
    - 1932, "Both Your Houses" (Box 1)
    - 1934, "Valley Forge" (Box 1)
    - 1935 (Box 1)
      - "The Wingless Victory" (Box 1)
      - "Wintersong" (Box 1)
    - 1936 (Box 1)
      - "High Tor" (Box 1)
      - "The Masque of Kings" (Box 1)
    - 1937 (Box 1)
      - "The Feast of Ortolans" (Box 1)
      - "Second Overture" (Box 1)
      - "The Star-Wagon" (Box 1)
    - 1939, "Key Largo" (Box 1)
    - 1940, "Journey to Jerusalem" (Box 2)
    - 1940, "Journey to Jerusalem" (Box 2)
    - 1941, "Candle in the Wind" (Box 2)
    - 1942, "The Eve of St. Mark" (Box 2)
    - 1943, "Storm Operation" (Box 2)
    - 1944, "The Greeks Remember Marathon" (Box 2)
    - 1945, "Truckline Café" (Box 2)
    - 1948, "Anne of the Thousands Days" (Box 2)
    - 1949, "Lost in the Stars" (Box 2)
    - 1951, "Barefoot in Athens" (Box 2)
    - 1953, "Carmen" (Box 2)
    - 1955, "The Bad Seed" (Box 2)
  - Drafts, galleys, and annotated copies (Box 3)
    - "Anne of the Thousand Days," 1948 (Box 3)
    - "Both Your Houses," 1932 (Box 3)
    - "Candle in the Wind," 1941 (Box 3)
    - "The Eve of St. Mark," 1942, (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - "Joan of Lorraine" (Box 4)
      - Screenplay, filmed as Joan of Arc (Box 4)
        - Notes by Alan Anderson, 1989 (Box 4)
        - Text, 1948, (5 folders) (Box 4)
      - Stage play, undated See Oversize (Box 4)
    - "Journey to Jerusalem," 1940 (Box 5)
    - "Key Largo," 1939, (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - "Second Overture," undated (Box 5)
    - "Valley Forge," 1936 (Box 5)
    - "What Price Glory," undated (Box 6)
    - "Winterset," undated See Oversize (Box 6)
- Oversize (Box OV 1)
  - Scripts (Box OV 1)
    - Drafts, galleys, and annotated copies (Box OV 1)
      - "Joan of Lorraine," undated (Container 4) (Box OV 1)
      - "Winterset," undated (Container 6) (Box OV 1)